<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on David Molefe</title>
    <link>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on David Molefe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Plane booking predictive model</title>
      <link>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Overview:
In this project, I aimed at developing a machine learning project which would help airlines determine whether a customer would complete a booking or not. Airlines have realized that the buying cycle has changed in today&amp;rsquo;s time, if you are hoping that customers would buy your tickets as they come to the airport you&amp;rsquo;ve already lost so airlines want to take a more proactive approach to getting more customers booking with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Movie Recommender System</title>
      <link>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>This has to be one of the intense project I have worked on in my early days of Data Science, I was in a team that was tasked to develop a movie recommender system using the unsupervised technique called recommender systems. We built this recommender system and deployed it using streamlit and made it accessible by internet using AWS.
We used movie lens dataset to complete this project, we downloaded the multiple files for the movie lens dataset and used them to accomplish our project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Language Identification Program</title>
      <link>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Also enjoyed doing this project it&amp;rsquo;s a very simple project, I had dataset from NCHLT Text Corpora collected by the South African Department of Arts and Culture &amp;amp; Centre for Text Technology that contained 11 official South African languages. I had to build a program that will classify a sentence as to which language does it belong to.
As with all project we started by cleaning the data we will be using to train our model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Classification of Tweets</title>
      <link>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>In this project we were given a dataset that consisted of Tweets, we had to work on a classification model to classify whether a Tweet is from a user who believes in man-made climate change or not, this project is intense on the Natural Language Processing techniques. It was a great project to work on and it made me excited on the unending opportunites that Machine Learning present.
Began with Data Cleaning to remove all duplicates, punctuations, url links and special symbols that were not necessary for our model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Predicting Energy Shortfall</title>
      <link>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://David-230.github.io/david_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>As the world grapples with the crisis of climate change many countries are looking into moving more towards clean energy, I was working in a team that was given a project to work on predicting a load shortfall between electricity produced by fossil fuels and renewables.
We were given a dataset with historical weather conditions in different cities in Spain as features and the Load Shortfall.
We began with cleaning our dataset to ensure that our analysis and model will be accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
